Guide to the Jewish Institute for Medical Research, 1959-2019 MS 922
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Jewish Institute for Medical Research Records
1959-2019
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Goodfriend, Barry H., Dr.
MS 922
.50 Linear Feet 1 box
This collection consists of one box containing correspondence, meeting materials, photographs, news clippings, etc. pertaining to the history and operations of the Jewish Institute for Medical Research from 1959-2019.
Biographical / Historical
Through a federal grant and the donations of more than 900 people, the Jewish Institute for Medical Research was established in coordination with the Baylor College of Medicine in 1959. The Institute has conducted research on and gathered support and awareness on a number of medical conditions, notably organizing city-wide screening for Tay-Sachs Disease.
Excerpted from https://blogs.bcm.edu/2013/11/08/commemorating-50th-anniversary-of-jewish-institute-for-medical-research-at-baylor/.
Content Description
One box of administrative materials, articles, event materials, photographs, and promotional materials document some of the work conducted by the Jewish Institute for Medical Research from 1959-2019.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials open for research.
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center and requires 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Dr. Barry Goodfriend, December 2019.
Arrangement
The materials in this collection have been arranged in six series as follows:
Series I: Administrative Materials; Series II: Articles; Series III: Event Materials; Series IV: Photographs; Series V: Promotional Materials; Sereis VI: Baylor College of Medicine
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Goodfriend, Barry H., Dr.
- Series I: Adminstrative materials
  - Meeting Minutes and Agendas, 1959-1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1959-2013 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Forms, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Funding Reports, 1964-2013 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bylaws, Articles of Incorporation, and Policies, 1985-1999 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Members Contact Info, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Tay Sachs Prevention Program Documents, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series II: Articles
  - News clippings, 1959-2013 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Articles, 1988-2006 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series III: Event Materials
  - Speeches, 1959-2013 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Programs, 1960-2013 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Awards, 1985-2000 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Presentations, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Map, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Series IV: Photographs
  - Photographs - groundbreaking and dedication, 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Photographs, 1982-2019 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Photograph of Dr. Farfel and thank you letter, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Series V: Promotional Materials
  - Promotional Material— General, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Promotional Materials— Tay Sachs Screening, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Series VI: Baylor College of Medicine
  - Baylor College of Medicine Resolution, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Baylor College of Medicine Publications, 1963-2006 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Book Dedicated to Dr. Goodfriend (Box 1)